A Guide to the Papers of Thomas Joseph Reilly 1925-1976
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Papers of Thomas Joseph Reilly 1925-1976
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
MG 8
5 Hollinger document cases; 2 linear feet
Administrative Information
Access
Open to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mary McPhillips Reilly, May 1976.
Biographical/Historical Information
Thomas Joseph (Tom) Reilly (1915-1976) was a political reporter for the Ledger-Star (Norfolk, Va.) and the Norfolk Ledger-Dispatch for twenty-six years. He graduated in 1933 from Maury High School in Norfolk and became a part-time copy boy on the Ledger-Dispatch a year later. In 1935 he began to work full-time for the newspaper and the following year he was assigned to cover the police and fire departments. He also wrote on sports and he was subsequently assigned to courts. In 1939 he was assigned to cover the military and waterfront beat. Soon after reporting the departure of the first contingent of draftees sent to Army camps from the Norfolk Union Station, Reilly joined the military himself. His first assignment was to start a public information office with the Army Air Corps at Goodfellow Field, Texas. He received his commission in 1942 and was sent to Casablanca during the North African invasion to assist in building an airfield for the 52nd Fighter Group. He remained with this outfit for thirty-two months through the campaigns of North Africa, Sicily, Corsica, and Italy.
Reilly left the service with the rank of captain. He returned to the Ledger-Dispatch as a general assignment reporter and was soon appointed assistant city editor, a position that he held for four years. He began to cover the General Assembly in 1948 on a part-time basis and two years later he covered the entire session. His reporting of the General Assembly and state and local politics over the next generation was distinguished for its accuracy, clarity, and balance. He expressed his philosophy of political reporting in the following words: "It takes time to get to know them [public figures] and they're understandably very sensitive. If they feel they're getting a fair shake, that's really all they expect and want... I don't concern myself if a story is going to be favorable or unfavorable to any particular candidate. It's going to be written on the basis of fact, not opinion... "
Scope and Content Information
Reilly's papers, dating from 1925-1976, include newspaper columns from the Ledger-Star (Norfolk, Va.) dealing with state and local politics, especially the sessions of the Virginia General Assembly. The collection also contains some clippings of columns from other newspapers regarding General Assembly sessions and small amounts of background material used in preparing certain of these columns. State Publications contained in the collection include: Election Results (1924-1973); Manuals of the Senate and the House of Delegates (1950-1974); Miscellaneous publications re: General Assembly (1942-1976).
Contents List
- Miscellaneous and Correspondence
  - General Correspondence 1974 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings about Reilly 1961-1975 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorabilia: Telephone Directory, 1968 Republican Convention (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Pictorial Records: Miscellaneous Photographs (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 4)
- Newspaper Columns (Clippings)
  - Miscellaneous 1972 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous 1973 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous 1974 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous 1975 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous 1975 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General Assembely Session 1975 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General Assembely Session 1976 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Material for Ledger-Star "Sidelights" Column: 1976 General Assembly Session-1971-1976 1971-1976, 1976 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ledger-Star Year-end Wrap-ups 1966-1969 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Ledger-Star Year-end Wrap-ups 1970-1973 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Material for Year-end Wrap-ups 1971-1973 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Interview with Porter Hardy, Jr. for column; miscellaneous material re. Hardy 1944-1972 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Material for Entry in Slover Contest 1975 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Columnists: Wrap-Ups of 1975 General Assembly Session 1975 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Richmond Columnists: 1976 General Assembely Session 1976 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Virginian-Pilot Columnists: 1976 General Assembely Session 1976 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 9)
- State publications
  - Election Results
    - Election Results 1924-1929 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Election Results 1930-1938 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Election Results 1940-1949 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Election Results 1950-1952 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Election Results 1953-1955 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Election Results 1956-1957 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Election Results 1958-1959 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Election Results 1960-1963 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Election Results 1964-1965 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Election Results 1966-1969 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Election Results 1970-1973 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bound Manuals of the Senate and House of Delegates of Virginia
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1950 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1952 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1954 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1954 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1956 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1958 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1958 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1960 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1962 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1964 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1964 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1966 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1968 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1968 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1970 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1970 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1972 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1972 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1972 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1974 (Box Box 4)
    - Manual of the Senate and House of Delegates 1974 (Box Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous State Publications
    - Reference Book: Virginia House of Delegates 1942 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Acts of the General Assembely, Extra Session 1969 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Constitution of Virginia 1971 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Biographies of Members of the Senate and the House of Delegates 1974 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Senate: Procedures Manual (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Senate: Rules 1976 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Lists of Members and Districts of General Assembely 1976 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 7)
    - General Assembely Committee Assignments 1974 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 8)
    - General Assembely Committee Assignments 1976 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Addresses, Phone Numbers of General Assembly Members 1974, 1976 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Campbell Commission Report of Suffrage Laws 1946 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Election Laws April 5, 1974 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Election Laws July 1, 1975 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 13)
    - The Virginia State Capitol 1974 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 14)